all right
[Music]
chronic kidney disease is one of the top
10 leading causes of premature death in
the United States and its incidence is
increasing
chronic kidney disease affects more than
10 percent of the adult population and
each year more than a hundred thousand
Americans develop end-stage kidney
disease and have to go on dialysis
what's crazy is that a staggering 96
percent of individuals with mild to
moderate decreases in kidney function
and about half of individuals with
severely decreased kidney function go
undiagnosed meaning the vast majority
like 24 out of 25 people with chronic
kidney disease don't even know they have
it
what can we do to maintain our kidney
function well in a study that followed
more than a thousand older women for a
decade those consuming a diet that was
richer in plant-based protein had a
slower decline in kidney function
extending support for the health
benefits of plant-rich diets in the
general population to maintain Kidney
Health
compared with protein from plant sources
animal protein has been associated with
an increased risk of end-stage kidney
disease in several such studies we're
not exactly sure why kidney damage from
animal protein could result from the
dietary acid load excess phosphorus or
gut microbiome bad bacteria and the
resultant inflammation the dietary acid
load in a standard American diet is
derived mostly from animal sources such
as meats eggs and cheeses in contrast by
including a higher proportion of foods
with natural Alkali such as fruits and
vegetables a strictly plant-based diet
is nearly acid neutral even just eating
plant-based two or three days a week can
significantly bring down the acid load
delivered to the kidneys and eating
plant-based full-time and you can
actually flip over into alkaline
territory
even just cutting out meat can yield the
alkaline load compared to the acid load
in the non-vegetarians all this is
important since dietary acid May promote
kidney injury and a progressive decline
in kidney function
it's the intake of animal protein can
also cause an imbalance in the
composition of the gut microbiome by
producing more ammonia and the rotten
egg gas hydrogen sulfide and have a
pro-inflammatory effect that may result
in reduced kidney function but it also
may be the animal fat and the Harvard
nurses study higher intake of animal fat
was directly associated with a loss of
protein in the urine which is a sign of
kidney damage and to protect against
that they suggest diets lower in animal
protein animal fat and cholesterol that
may help explain why vegetarians have
better kidney function than
non-vegetarians matched for sex age size
physical activity alcohol smoking Etc so
effectively even a meat eater who is
just as Slim as a vegetarian just as
healthy cholesterol blood pressure and
blood sugar control wise still has
inferior kidney function they think it
might be the higher dietary fiber intake
on more plant-based diets contributing
to the protective effect on kidney
function again three
microbiomechanism whereas the
consumption of animal protein may lead
to a proliferation of meat eating bugs
which can result in a leaky gut uremic
toxins and resulting inflammation
oxidative stress and chronic kidney
disease progression that can be blocked
with the decreased inflammation and
acetode thanks to the eating of More
fiber-rich Foods no wonder an egg-free
vegetarian dietary pattern was
associated with a 37 decreased odds of
developing chronic kidney disease but
what about plant-based diets for not
just the prevention but the management
of chronic kidney disease can
comprehensive lifestyle change alter the
course of chronic kidney disease this
was the case report if someone diagnosed
with minimal changes disease that's when
someone's kidneys start leaking protein
even though there are minimal changes
seen in biopsies under the microscope
you give people steroids and in a few
months you can knock it down but a
significant fraction may fail to respond
to the steroid therapy he was diagnosed
18 years prior but only by replacing
animal protein with plant-based protein
was he able to put his chronic kidney
disease into remission
at age 44 he suddenly developed swelling
that crept up throughout his body since
he was losing so much protein he was
weak unable to concentrate lethargic
diagnosed with minimal change disease
and treated with a water pill and four
different blood pressure lowering agents
because of unresponsiveness to high dose
steroids a powerful immunosuppressant
was added yet severe protein loss
continued and his hypertension and
kidney function worsened until he
started eating plant-based started
exercising lost 60 pounds in his kidney
disease went away and stayed away let's
hear it in his own words I appreciate
the recommendations my doctor gave me
about making dietary modifications
replace your protein intake with
plant-based protein this one change has
had a Monumental impact on my life I've
gained back a quality of life that I
thought was gone forever my Benchmark
for normal has been my ability to keep
up with my professional work demands and
still be able to exercise for the last
seven months I now swim over three miles
every other day a distance that
surpasses my pre-kidney disease life I
perceived I lived a healthy lifestyle
before kidney disease today I live a
healthier happier lifestyle and I have
my kidneys to thank for it
foreign